Guide to the Brooklyn Historical Society mixed ephemera collection ARC.314
Brooklyn Historical Society
Brooklyn Historical Society mixed ephemera collection
1783-1994
Brooklyn Historical Society
ARC.314
2 linear feet in 2 record cartons
This collection contains pamphlets, brochures, playbills, catalogs, programs and other materials dating from 1783 to 1994 and relating to a range of individuals, families, and institutions from Brooklyn, Long Island and the Hudson Valley region. The collection was compiled by library staff at the Brooklyn Historical Society.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in alphabetical order by folder title.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Immediate source of acquisition unknown. This collection was artifically compiled by Brooklyn Historical Society staff.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials dating from 1783 to 1994. The majority of the items are the product of institutions – i.e. businesses, churches, municipal services - though there are a few booklets by individuals, and one hand-drawn family tree. Topics range from advertisements to invitations to fundraising balls to a treatise on human perfectibility. This is a varied collection of disparate materials which were previously part of the Brooklyn Historical Society vertical files.
Biographical / Historical
This collection was compiled by Brooklyn Historical Society staff. These materials were previously part of the BHS vertical files collection, but were physcially removed from vertical files at an unknown date.
Theaters |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Banks and banking; Economic development |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Clubs |z New York (State) |z New York; Genealogy -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Trade catalogs; Advertisements; Long Island (N.Y.) |x Commerce; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Commerce; Circuses (performances); Sermons; Tourism |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Prison Ship Martyrs' Monument (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Staten Island (New York, N.Y.); Trains; Prospect Park (New York, N.Y.); Taxicab industry |z New York (State) |z New York; Long Island Railroad Company.; Montauk Theatre (Organization: Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)); Moore, Marianne; Nostrand family
- Adelphi Academy pamphlet, located on Lafayette Ave in Fort Green, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Albany Academy 'historical sketch' pamphlet, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Total Abstinence Society membership card, circa 1850 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Apollo Club of Brooklyn, program for concert at Academy of Music, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Baldwin, G. Views of the Adirondacks, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Goodyear, William Henry (curator), Italian exhibit catalog, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Browne's Commercial Academy advertisement, 1864-1865 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Barber, Edwin Bruce, historical sketch of Greenpoint Porcelain Works, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Burning of the Brooklyn Theatre," illustrated pamphlet describing the incident, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Barnum and Bailey Greatest Show on Earth Review and Magazine, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bayle's Long Island Handbook (with gazetteer), Middle Island, NY, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bliss, E.W. and Co. Catalog, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bocklin, A., "Masters in Art: A Series of Illustrated Monographs," periodical, March 1906 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bouguereau, W.A., "Masters in Art: A Series of Illustrated Monographs," periodical, October 1906 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bowdoin, W.G., Childish art in old samplers, "Fashion Digest," periodical, Winter 1940 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Judge Bronson, Kings Co. Court House (opinion piece published in Brooklyn Daily Eagle), 1854 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Brooklyn travel writing, from TWA's magazine, Side Streets, and Crain's New York Business, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Brighton Beach Racing Association, Coney Island, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Bristed, C.A., "Warning… Consequences of a Railroad in Fifth Avenue", 1863 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Brooklyn Athenaeum, catalog of first exhibition, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Brooklyn Academy of Music, program, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Brooklyn Children's Aid Society, card advertising benefit fair, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Brooklyn Common Council, Law Committee report, City property at foot of Fulton Street, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Brooklyn Common Council, To the Citizens of Brooklyn, By order of the Water Committee, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Brooklyn Heights Players, program for "The Romantic Young Lady", 1926 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, Sights Seen from Brooklyn Heights, 1783-1890 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Church of the Holy Trinity, Discourses at Opening, Reverend William H. Lewis, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Brooklyn Bridge Waltz, A. Hoffman and C. Bunce, (photocopy), 1875 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Brooklyn, Report of the Committee of the East Side Lands, Board of Park Commissioners, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Brooklyn, Department of Parks, Report on Destruction of the Cottony Maple Scale, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Brooklyn Theatre Fire Relief Association, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Brooklyn Veteran's Handbook, circa 1945 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Brooklyn Celebration of the introduction of the Nassau Water, City of Brooklyn c. 1, April 27, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Brooklyn Celebration of the introduction of the Nassau Water, City of Brooklyn c.2, April 27, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Brown, G.L., ed., Father Comstock and the First Congregational Church of Lewis, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Bureau of Catholic Indian Missions, The work of the decade… 1883, Washington DC, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Burton, G., Long Island Oil-Fisheries, from "Appleton's Journal," periodical, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Butler, G. B., Croton - Water Supply, New York Municipal Society, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Brooklyn Bridge Re-unveiling Celebration, program, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Civilian Welfare Association, Annual Dance program, Manhattan, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Callendar, Will, pamphlet, Souvenir of the Old Dutch Mansion, Greenbush, NY, circa 1890 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- California Indian Association, two pamphlets, "New Mission" and "To the Christian People", circa 1909 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Carlton Theater (movie theater), program for Corinne Griffith in "Infatuation", Brooklyn, circa 1926 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Catholic Clergy of Oregon, Address on President Grant's Indian Policy, Portland, OR, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Catholic Commissioners for Indian Missions, President Grant's Peace Policy, Washington, DC, circa 1875 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Central Sunday School Union, program, Anniversary Celebration, Flatbush, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Charles, Heinrich, The Romance of the Name America, along with promotional materials, New York, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Cincinnati Historical Society, The Great Suspension Bridge at Cincinnati, OH, Centennial Year, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- City Reform Club, What Are You Going to Do About It? Assemblymen and Senators, City of New York, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- The Colonial (a quarterly), periodical, June and December issues, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Coney Island Velodrome, program, May 27, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Conover, G.S., Sayenqueraghta, King of the Senecas, biographical pamphlet, Geneva, N.Y, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Catalogue of the late John M. Falconer, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- P. Derby and Co. Chairs Catalogue (item missing), 1909 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- DeKalb Theatre pamplet, "Smart Styles", April 1914 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Edouart, August, 1789-1861, Catalogue of 3,800 named and dated American dilhouette Portraits (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Eldridge, George, Sailing directions for Edlridge's new chart of Long Island Sound, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Emerald Association, program for Eighty-Seventh Charity Ball program at the Waldorf Astoria, February 4, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Emeric-David, Toussaint Bernard, Essai sur la classement chronologique des sculpteurs Grecs les plus celebres, 1807 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Erasmus Hall High School, The Erasmian, annual student publication, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Erie Lines Complete Time Tables, February 1893 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Evarts, William, Opinion on qualification of voters, circa 1860 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- The Falconer library of art books, manuscripts, etc. pamphlet, includes photograph of Albert Durer's house, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Library of the late John M. Falconer relating to the history and practice of the fine arts, Anderson Auction Company pamphlet, December 28, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Fire alarm box directions, circa 1884 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Field, T.W., Nicasius DeSille appendix, undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Folsom, Merrill, 1683 mill is back in Sleep Hollow as Philipse Castle keeps growing (photocopy, published in The New York Times), April 3, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Green, Henry J., Scientific Instruments catalog, undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Fox Playhouse at Great Neck, Long Island, theater program for "Hokus Pokus", September 21, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Fryer, William J., Site for new U.S. public buildings in the city of New York, pamphlet no. 4, August 18, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Gallagher (D.F.) and Co., embossed steel ceilings (item missing), undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Garden City Company pamphlet, undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Program for Gilmore's Band concerts, Manhattan Beach, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Program for Gilmore's Band concerts, Manhattan Beach, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Glimpses of Brooklyn with 25 illustrations from recent photographs, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Gooderson Engine Company No. 2, fiftieth anniversary souvenir, Winfield, Long Island, May 30, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Hotel Granada brochure, with letter, undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Gouveneur, NY 1st Presbyterian Church, Centennial Historical Discourse, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Grand Opera House, Brooklyn, pamphlet, advertisements, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Grand Union Tea Company, Brooklyn, Illustrated Catalogue of Useful and Ornamental Household Supplies, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Gravesend Exempt Volunteer Firemen: East Rockaway Fire Dept., annual ball materials, 1894-1914 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Greenleaf Female Institute, on Brooklyn Heights, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 82)
- Guignard, Ph, Notice historique sur la vie et las travaux de M. Fevret de Saint-Memin, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Hall, Edward Hagaman, Central Park in the City of New York, 16th annual report (includes photos and maps), circa 1814 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Harrison, William Henry, A discourse on the aborigines of the valley of the Ohio, published in Boston, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 85)
- Hawes, L.W., Lewiston: past, present and future, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 86)
- Heckscher Museum, Land of Whitman, a special exhibition, Huntington, NY, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 87)
- Hollister, Isaac, A brief narrative of the captivity of Isaac Hollister, published in Townsend, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 88)
- Hoosick Falls, NY, First Baptist Church, manual, November 1888 (Box 1, Folder 89)
- Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission, Official Program: Hudson-Fulton Celebration, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 90)
- Hudson, NY, First Presbyterian Church, centennial celebration, February 23, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 91)
- Johnstown, NY, First Presbyterian Church, early history, November 24, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 92)
- Kings County Historical Society, assorted programs, 1911-1919 (Box 1, Folder 93)
- Kingsboro, NY, Presbyterian Church, historical record by the pastor George Harkness, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 94)
- Leeds, NY, Reformed Protestant Dutch Church ( Reformed Church of Old Katskill), article from the Examiner, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 95)
- Leesville, NY, Leesville Baptist Church, semi-centennial, October 1, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 96)
- Lenox Lyceum, NY City, Anton Seidl's Popular Sunday Concerts, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 97)
- Midwout Magazine, vol. 5, no. 7, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 98)
- Processing of the coroner in the case of the Steamer Lexington, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 99)
- Livingston, John A. against the City of Brooklyn, statement of facts, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 100)
- Long Island Railroad Company, Unique Long Island, pamphlet (primarily photos), undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
- Long Island Railroad, pamphlet, Along the sunrise trails of Long Island, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 102)
- Long Island Canal and Navigation Co., pamphlet, Report on the project of uniting the great bays of Long Island by canals, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 103)
- Long Island Business College, 36th annual graduating exercises, June 17, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 104)
- Howard Orphanage and Industrial School, Kings Park, pamphlet (fragile), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 105)
- Homer, Winslow, Twelve scenes of nineteenth century America, 1836-1910 (Box 1, Folder 106)
- Keeseville, NY Congregational Church manual, September, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 107)
- Kenny, J., Illustrated price list of stock cuts for printing purposes, undated (Box 1, Folder 108)
- Hymnal in the Seneca Indian language, Albion, NY, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 109)
- Luna Park, 13 Spook Street: the old haunted castle on the Midway, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- New Brighton Theatre pamphlet, Coney Island, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Minisink Valley Historical Society, 1690-1890 bicentennial celebration, July 22, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lindsly, A.B., Net cash price list (item missing), 1878 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Sheepshead Bay Board of Trade, pamphlet, views of Sheepshead Bay, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Long Island via the Long Island Railroad pamphlet, 1868 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Brooklyn and LI matchbook cover advertisements, 1939-1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Dinner to Dr. St. Clair McKelway by the Lotus Club, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- McElroy, Samuel, Water-power at Niagara Falls pamphlet, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- The Majestic Theatre, program, March 18, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Manhattan bridge, exercises at the celebration of the opening at the Brooklyn Club, December 31, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Marlborough, NY Presbyterian Church, A centennial discourse and A quarter century discourse, 1864-1867 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Mechanics Bank of Brooklyn articles of association, with Soup House Association Fragile, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Melish, Rev. William Howard, sermon: "The Great Chancel Window", St. Ann and the Holy Trinity, July 18, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Metropolitan Life Building pamphlet, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Mitchell, H.B., pamphlet, Meditation, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Mohonk Lake Mountain House, information for prospective guests, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Montauk Beach Development Corp, pamphlet, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- The Montauk Theatre Brooklyn, 2 programs, 1915-1922 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Morgan, T.J., Indian education, published for Bureau of Education in Washington D.C., 1890 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Melrose Park, Flatbush pamphlet, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Marianne Moore, Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church of Brooklyn memorial booklet, February 8, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- New York Banks glee club programs, 1885-1886 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Newberry, Edward, pamphlet on Human Perfectibility, 1878 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- The New Montauk Theatre Brooklyn (photocopy), 1906 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- New York State Education Department, Major aboriginal projectil points in NYS, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- New York City, Triborough Bridge Authority, pamphlet, Sheepshead Bay section of the Belt Parkway, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Niagara Co., NY, History of the Presbytery of Niagara 1824-1887, Lockport, NY (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Nicoll, H., Early History of Suffolk County, Long Island, 1866 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Northfield, NY, Centennial Celebration of the 4th of July, Richmond County (Staten Island), 1876 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Nostrand, Peter F., Nostrand family research, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Olmsted, Frederick Law, et al, A letter introductory, Staten Island Improvement Commission, 1871 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Onandaga County Centennial, Historical address delivered in Reformed Dutch Church, Syracuse, NY, May 27, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Ostrander Family Association pamphlet, Ostrander: from the east bank, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Owego, NY, Congretational Church and Society manual, September 1, 1874 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Pierce and Son, office chair catalogue, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Pierce and Son/Piercecraft, office chair catalogue, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Prospect Park Band Concert program, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Theater items, assorted: Park Theater, Shubert Crescent Theatre, Brooklyn Volks Theatre, 1875-1920 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Parascandola Collection (tintype, photo, cards), 1883-1908 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Peet, Louis Harman letters to Henry Haviland, 1902-1903 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Pratt and Co. astral oil advertisement (photocopy), undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Pelton, Henry, Recollections of the early history of Warwick, NY, 1872 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Pelletreau, William S., Old Southampton, The Long Island Magazine, September 1893 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Peters, A., The City of the Silent: A tribute to the Woodlawn Cemetery, May 1866 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Paris Salon: illustrated catalog, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Pfeiffer, Carl, Sanitary relations to health principles in architecture, American Public Health Association, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Pilcher, Lewis S., Croup and Tracheotomy in the City of Brooklyn, NY, April 17, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Prospect Park: 1866-1966, Centennial Committee pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Rainey, Thomas, The Long Island Bridge, papers, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Dutcher, Silas B., Ramapo Water Company reply to The Controller of the City of New York, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Reynolds, Florence Leary, Reminiscenses of Ossining, Mohegan Chaper D.A.R., 1922 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Ringling Bros. Barnum and Bailey Magazine and Daily Review, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Ripolin, Colonial Series for Architects, J.A. and W. Bird and Co., 1916 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Rockwood and Company Cocoa and Chocolate Factory, National Register of Historic Places, December 17, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Rogers, Ray, Hand Stenciling: A good post-war career, I. Fraser publisher, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Romney, O.W., The New York Salt Springs and a glance at the Salt Laws, Faxon's Power Press, Buffalo, 1864 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Roycrofters, The Roycroft books: A catalog and some remarks, East Aurora, NY, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Sylvan Electric Bath, Inc. pamphlet, Schermerhorn Street, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Sam S. Shubert Theatre, Monroe Investing Co., Frank V. Straussand Co. publishers, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Shubert Crescent Theatre weekly program (photocopy of cover), 1920 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Smith, Franklin W., Design and Prospectus for the National Gallery of History and Art, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Simon, Donald E., Historic Prospect Park, NYC Parks Recreation and Cultural Affairs Administration, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Spooner, Shearjashub, An appeal to the people of the U.S. in behalf of art, artists and public weal, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Sprague, William B., discourse for fiftieth anniversary of the Second Presbyterian Church, Albany, September 3, 1865 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Sprague, William B., serom addressed to the Second Presbyterian Church, Albany, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Vosburgh, Royden Woodward, The history of Zion's Evangelical Lutheran Church of Cobleskill, November 1916 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- St. Ann's Church, The St. Ann's Extra, vol. 1, no. 4, February 20, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Staten Island Historical Society pamphlet, The historic Village of Richmond and vicinity, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Steuben County Board of Elections, list of enrolled voters in the City of Hornell, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Stoddard, S.R., The Adirondacks Illustrated, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Syracuse Ornamental Company catalog, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- The Taxi Traveler: In and around New York, vol. 1, no. 1, Taxi Advertising Corp. publisher, June 28, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Sinclair Tousey, from the National Cyclopedia pf American Biography, James T. White and Co. publisher, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Titus, Freelove R., deed to S. Laurence and J. Willard, 1823 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Taylor, George, Martyrs to the revolution in the British prison-ships in the Wallabout Bay, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- To the Whig and Democratic electors of Brooklyn and County of Kings, Sacket and Co. printers, circa 1850 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- U.S. Naval Reserve pamphlet, Review of the Second Battalion, N.Y.N.M. U.S. Naval Reserve, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- United States Railroad Administration pamphlet, Long Island travel guide, undated (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Village of Ossining pamphlet (includes map), undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
- Vrooman, Col. John W., Centennial celebration of the Village of Herkimer, on the churches of Herkimer, August 6, 1907 - August 8, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- Swan, Laurel Brill, Chart of the descendants of Meyer Hochster (Hexter) and Cela Lorsch, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Souvenir of the fair in aid of the Steamer Fund of Wandowenock Fire, Hook and Ladder Company No. 1, April 22, 1890 -April 26, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 83)
- War Fund Committee pamphlet, Services and addresses at the unveiling of the statue of Abraham Lincoln, Brooklyn, October 21, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 84)
- West, Chas E., The Prison Ship Martyrs: Horrors of the prison ships - in aid of the monument being erected to the Martyrs by the Daughters of the Revolution; Handbook of Mount Vernon replica), 1895 (Box 2, Folder 85)
- Program for the Fourth Annual Testimonial Dinner and Dancce of the Veteran Boxers Association of Brooklyn, Ring 21, in honor of Johnny Addie and Mannie Seamon, October 31, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 86)
- Werba's Brooklyn Theatre, 7 programs published by New York Theatre Program Corporation, 1926-1929 (Box 2, Folder 87)
- Whitaker, Epher, The American union of church and state, past and present, an address delivered to the Suffolk County Historical Society, June 14, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 88)
- Wiltwyck Chapter, Daughters of the American Revvolution, program for an historial pageant, December 9, 1895 - December 14, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 89)
- Winter, Frederick A., Excavating New York City: Brooklyn (photocopy from Archaeology, an official publication of the Archaological Institute of America), January 1981 - February 1981 (Box 2, Folder 90)
- Youman's New York, fall and winter 1897-1898 hat catalogue (Box 2, Folder 91)
- The Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor presents "Come Out of the Kitchen" by A.E. Thomas, March 14, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 92)
- Zuffanelli, Giuseppe e Faglia, Francesco; La Faciate del Duomo di Firenze, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 93)
- Younger, William Lee; The New England Society in the City of Brooklyn: the first forty years, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 94)
- Y.M.C.A., Popular songs of the A.E.F., 1918 (Box 2, Folder 95)